Alberto Vergel

avergel.co.uk

linkedin.com/in/albertovergel

hello@avergel.co.uk

PROFILE

Manchester based Senior **Java Developer** with 8 years of experience, mainly developing Java applications using **Spring**, JPA and several database engines, TDD and Agile. Good problem solver, proactive and highly motivated. Excellent teamwork skills and a great willingness to learn new technologies. Hard-worker, efficient, solution-oriented, calm under pressure and great social skills.

SUMMARY SKILLS

- Java 8, Java EE 6
- Spring 4 Suite (Boot, Data, JPA, MVC, AMQP, REST).
- Java Tools for database use: **Hibernate**, MyBatis.
- SQL databases: Oracle, MySql, MariaDB, Sql Server. No-SQL databases: MongoDB
- Search engines: Elasticsearch.
- Continuous integration and project management tools: Jenkins, JIRA, Confluence, Chef.
- Code management tools: Git, Bitbucket, CVS, SVN.
- Frameworks and Java technologies: JSF, Primefaces, Struts, JSP, JSTL, JasperReports.
- Task automation and library dependencies tools: Maven, Ant.
- IDE: IntelliJ IDEA, Eclipse.
- Unit Testing tools: Junit, Mockito
- Agile development environment, Scrum.
- Application servers: **Apache Tomcat**, JBoss, Glassfish.

WORK HISTORY

Black Swan Data: Oct 2015 – Aug 2017

- Development of microservices (using Spring and RabbitMQ) to stream data from various social platforms (Facebook, Google, Twitter, Youtube, Instagram), storing and indexing it using SQL systems (MySQL and MariaDB), no-SQL (MongoDB) and Elasticsearch, in order to derive analytics/insights.
- Suggest & develop solutions during transformation stages with fast delivery timelines.
- Teamworking in an agile environment, following Scrum scheme for meetings and deliveries.

Drago Solutions: Sep 2011 - Sep 2015

- Task analysis including estimation of time and resources. Participation in all the stages of the software development cycle.
- Java Applications development using Hibernate, Spring MVC and JSF (Primefaces) with Oracle, MySql and Sql Server databases for major clients from the energy industry and the service sector. Development and execution of unit tests.

Softoro Development Center: Sep 2009 – Aug 2011

- Web portal development using OpenCms, Wordpress, Joomla and Drupal.
- PL/SQL procedures development.

EDUCATION

BSc in Computer Science – University of Salamanca (Spain), 2012